Nataly Smith

Github: https://github.com/nmprojects LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/nataly-smith/

Portfolio Website: https://astrogirlnim.github.io/portfolio/

ABOUT ME

Senior Software Developer who specializes in full-stack app development, mathematical modeling, with expertise in cloud technologies/infrastructure and pipeline architecture. Mixing Python, C#, and custom Bash/Shell scripting for most projects, experience with many other languages and frameworks for professional development. Avid learner of the latest tools and platforms; currently exploring computer hardware, AI, and the global internet.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Python, R, C#, C, C++, VB, Bash, Matlab, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Racket, Lisp Languages

.NET, WPF/XAML, Scikit, OpenCV, Flask, ReactJS, NextFlow, Luigi Docker, Git, PostgreSQL, IIS, Visual Studio, VS Code, Vincent Co Frameworks

Tools

Linux, Web, Google Cloud Platform, Azure, AWS, JIRA, GitHub, Bitbucket **Platforms**

Concepts OOP, SOLID, Agile Development, Unit and Integration Testing, Mathematical Modeling, Machine Learning

Soft Skills Communication, Problem-Solving, Collaboration, Discipline

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer, CAS Project

Remote

Bruker NANO, formerly PhenomeX

March 2023 - Present

- o Completed a full-scale Azure DevOps migration in record 3 months by coordinating team efforts, automating migration processes, and creating custom programmatic tools.
- Expedited application runtime by 75% with code rewrite, hitting product specifications with an on-time release.
- Built critical testing functionality ahead of schedule, expediting product release by 2 weeks.
- Enriched deployment life cycle and scalability through Docker and CI/CD orchestration technologies.
- Constructed a multi-cloud implementation of Genomic sequencing testing infrastructure.

Senior Software Developer, Duomic Project

Remote

IsoPlexis Corp., a PhenomeX Company

Dec 2022 - March 2023

- Increased critical application performance by 400% by leading a re-architecture of existing code.
- Improved software quality and throughput by implementing DevOps pipeline refactoring and automated testing.
- Supported interdepartmental teamwork by developing python libraries, custom tools, and high-quality documentation to be shared and referenced.
- Worked with company leadership to create technology solutions that achieved high-level business goals.

Software Developer

Remote

IsoPlexis Corp., a PhenomeX Company

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

- o Main developer in creating research tools for next-gen sequencing.
- Independently developed a web portal that enabled interdepartmental teams to access research tools.
- Introduced automated unit testing and integration testing into our development packages.
- Worked with C++ computer vision libraries to improve our sequencing technologies.

Computer Systems Engineer

Remote

McMaster-Carr

Sep 2021 - Jan 2022

- o Improved company knowledge sharing and education by creating an internal communications hub.
- Worked with established SDLC that involved cross team coordination, testing, and release schedules.
- Delivered business value by developing website features end to end, including Database Schemas, Business Logic, REST API Implementation, and front-end development.
- Integrated legacy systems to interface with modern business-critical applications.

EDUCATION

Yale University

New Haven, CT

Bachelor of Science - Biomedical Engineering (Focus on Biocomputation); GPA: 3.64

August 2017 - May 2021

Courses and Areas of Study: Data Structures, Data Science, Analysis of Algorithms, Biomedical Imaging and Device Development, Computation for Research, Mathematical Modeling, High-Performance High-Throughput Programming, Memory Management

HONORS/AWARDS, OTHER

- Runner Up Yale CBIT (Center for Biomedical Innovation Technology) Healthcare Hackathon Jan 2021
- Tsai City Accelerator (Yale Tsai Center For Innovative Thinking) program Nov 2020.
- Yale Domestic Summer Award May 2020.
- Cum Laude. Vincent Cordova Diversity Award. National Hispanic Scholar. National Academy of Future Physicians and Medical Scientists Award of Excellence Nominee.
- Fluent in English, Spanish, French.

Email: nmmsoftware@gmail.com Mobile: +1-505-203-6058